A Guide to the Percy Wallace MacKaye Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #7431-c
Percy Wallace MacKaye Collection 1903-1913
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
7431-c
8 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Transfer 1989 August 29
Item Listing
- Letters
  - Percy MacKaye, Harvard Club, to Walter Prichard Eaton, 1908 Jan 9; ALS, 2 p.
    mentioning that he is to lecture on "The Drama of Democracy" before the MacDowell Association and also at Earl Hall, Columbia University, and wishing to see him while he is in town.
  - Percy MacKaye, San Francisco, California, to Walter Prichard Eaton, 1908 July 27; ALS, 1 p.
    concerning the production of his play
    Mater
  - Percy MacKaye, Cornish, New Hampshire, to Walter Prichard Eaton, 1908 Nov 8; ALS, 1 p.
    congratulating him on the loss of his job [from the New York
    Sun
    ?] which "may mean a black mark on your bank-account but it means a gold medal to you from the angels & the muses."
  - Percy MacKaye, The Players, to Walter Prichard Eaton, 1910 Nov 7; ALS, 4 p.
    thanking him for the article on
    Anti-Matrimony
    in the
    Chicago Record-Herald
    and expressing his gratitude for Eaton's emphasis on "the use of putting the whole body of modern European drama into a better perspective for Americans..."
  - Percy MacKaye, Cambridge, Massachusetts, to Walter Prichard Eaton, Stockbridge, Massachusetts, 1913 Jan 13; TLS w/env, 1 p.
    praising the excerpt of his lecture which appeared in the
    Transcript
  - Percy MacKaye, Harvard Club, to William Winter, a highly regarded contemporary of his father, [James Morrison] Steele MacKaye, 1903 Mar 20; ALS, 2 p.
    having taken the liberty of asking the MacMillan Company to send him a copy of MacKaye's play in verse,
    The Canterbury Pilgrims
    , and expressing his desire to have Winter's critical opinion of the play.
- Miscellaneous
  - Program for an open-air performance of The Canterbury Pilgrims by Percy MacKaye, 1909 May 25; Broadside
  - Newspaper clipping, " Walter P. Eaton's New York Letter" re Percy MacKaye's Anti-Matrimony, 1910 Oct 8; Printed